Frederic and Eileen Monaghan Whitaker Papers
Frederic Whitaker Papers
- Writings
  - Essays, typescripts of essays on various topics, by FW
    - Modernization of the Art Business, undated (Box 61)
    - Monstance, 1978 (Box 61)
    - Moving Left in Government and Art, undated (Box 61)
    - Municipal Art Society of New York History, 1948 (Box 61)
    - Negro Problem, 1967 (Box 61)
    - Non-art, 1971-1976; 3 folders (Box 61)
    - Not that much truth, 1977 (Box 61)
    - Odors, 1968 (Box 61)
    - Old Man in a Hurry, 1975 (Box 61)
    - Our Debt to Past Generations, 1975 (Box 61)
    - Painting from photographs (Box 61)
    - Painting / Value of Money, 1977 (Box 61)
    - Planting Seeds, 1973 (Box 61)
    - Poverty, 1975 (Box 61)
    - Poverty Problem, 1969 (Box 61)
    - The Power of Law, undated (Box 61)
    - Power of the Individual, 1975 (Box 61)
    - Pragmatism or Sentimentality, 1971 (Box 61)
    - Prejudice and Discrimination, undated (Box 61)
    - Production, 1976 (Box 61)
    - Production / Inflation, 1976 (Box 61)
    - Prosperity Is Contagious, 1967 (Box 61)
    - Prostitution, 1977 (Box 61)
    - Pursuit of Happiness, 1971 (Box 61)
    - Purveyors of Discourtesy, 1975 (Box 61)
    - Questions 11A amd 11B on improving high schools and colleges today, 1966 (Box 61)
    - Random Reflections on Matters Artistic, 1967-1972; 6 folders (Box 61)
    - Rattlesnakes, 1975 (Box 62)
    - Recollections, undated; 3 foldres (Box 62)
    - Reverie, 1975 (Box 62)
    - Rewards for Virtue and Valor, undated (Box 62)
    - Right Without Thinking, 1971 (Box 62)
    - Rights and Responsibilities, 1974 (Box 62)
    - Says the Boss, undated (Box 62)
    - Self-Education, undated (Box 62)
    - Shipwreck / Cape Cod, undated (Box 62)
    - Should the Rich Be Nationalized, undated (Box 62)
    - Social issues, 1970-1977; 3 folders (Box 62)
    - Solve Problems of Labor, Friction, Etc, 1971 (Box 62)
    - Somebody Else, 1975 (Box 62)
    - Source of Wealth, 1968 (Box 62)
    - South of the Border, undated (Box 62)
    - Speaking / Writing / Thinking, 1979 (Box 62)
    - The Spider, 1951 (Box 62)
    - Stop Talking, undated (Box 62)
    - Success, 1970 (Box 62)
    - Sudden Death / How It Feels, 1972 (Box 62)
    - Talking from the Book, undated (Box 62)
    - Tax Payer's Strike, 1971 (Box 62)
    - Technique, undated (Box 62)
    - Test Civilization, undated (Box 62)
    - The "Over" System, 1972 (Box 62)
    - The Debt to Our Forebears, 1970 (Box 62)
    - The -Ism Painters, undated (Box 62)
    - The Nature of Ferment, undated (Box 62)
    - Thoughts on Sex, undated (Box 62)
    - Thoughts While Listening, 1971 (Box 62)
    - To organize an art society (Box 62)
    - Today's Art / Take It Easy, 1955 (Box 62)
    - Value of Human Life, 1971 (Box 62)
    - Value of Time, undated (Box 62)
    - Wages, 1978 (Box 62)
    - Watercolor Painting, undated (Box 63)
    - We Can't Expect to Reach the Peak, 1971 (Box 63)
    - We Get What We Ask For, undated (Box 63)
    - We Think We Know What We Like, undated (Box 63)
    - Wealth, 1971 (Box 63)
    - We're a Tough Lot, 1955 (Box 63)
    - What's Wrong with Art Today?, 1968 (Box 63)
    - Who Exploits the Workers, 1977 (Box 63)
    - Who Owes What to Whom, 1969 (Box 63)
    - Who Wins Prizes - And Why, undated (Box 63)
    - Why Does Art Need to Be Explained?, undated (Box 63)
    - Women Are Different, undated (Box 63)
    - Women Overload Everything, 1971 (Box 63)
    - Women's Lib, 1975 (Box 63)
    - Women's Lib #2, 1977 (Box 63)
    - Word to Upcoming Generation, 1971 (Box 63)
    - Working Over Watercolors, 1955 (Box 63)
    - You Can Keep From Saying Anything, 1971 (Box 63)
  - Inspirational material for essays, undated (Box 63)
  - Letter to God, 1979 (Box 63)
  - Manuscripts
    - Autobiography (I Marched in the Parade), 1966 (Box 63)
      See also Autobiography, above.
    - Organizing a Painting, 1964 (Box 63)
    - Painting Perfection, undated; 2 folders (Box 63)
    - This Crazy Art Business, undated; 2 folders (Box 64)
    - This Crazy Art Business / The Artist and the Real World, undated (Box 64)
  - Poem, "I Play My Concertina", undated (Box 64)
  - Rules, undated (Box 64)
  - Miscellaneous, letters to the editor, "quotable quotes," blurbs for other artists' exhibits, etc.; 6 folders (Box 64)